<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nicholas Frota</title>
    <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nicholas Frota</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://***REMOVED***.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-01/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-02/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-03/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-04/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/art/illustration-05/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anamnese para o professor</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/personal/anamnese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/personal/anamnese/</guid>
      <description>Idade: 50 anos
Massa corporal total: 140 lb?
Altura: 6 feet
Restrições a atividade física? : Nenhuma
Tem diabetes, hipertensão ou outro ? : Não
Toma medicamentos ? Quais? :
Objetivo principal? : Primeiro recuperação da cirurgia de cotovelo&amp;hellip; Mas também crescer naturalmente, mantendo articulações e flexibilidade. Energia e qualidade de vida.
Nível de condicionamento? : Avançado (mas diminui um pouco por causa do acidente)
O que você não gosta de fazer nos treinos ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Privacy Residency (2025)</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/personal/apply/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/personal/apply/</guid>
      <description>Link: Community Privacy Residency (2025) form  Short bio I am an UX designer working for almost a decade for a scientific publisher heavily invested in open access, and volunteering as a community organizer for open source/P2P initiatives on the side.
What is your motivation for joining the Community Privacy Residency? What would you like to receive from our time together? What do you hope to contribute? Designing for open source is notoriously difficult, and I am looking for a more product-based approach to solutions, partnering with required stakeholders and community leaders from the start, for more robust, usable solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TODO</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/admin/todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/admin/todo/</guid>
      <description> create work project .gitignore work project from both content and published move projects to root? check ***REMOVED***.nyc freeform &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; script: image paths, obsidian &amp;ldquo;publish&amp;rdquo; script: zed, hugo serve, image paths, push?    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Animes</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/blog/anime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/blog/anime/</guid>
      <description>Frieren Dorohedoro Heavenly Delusion!!! Delicious in Dungeon </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free usability consulting for commons</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/consulting/</guid>
      <description>I’m an usability/UI-UX/product designer offering one-hour consulting sessions for open source projects.
In the session, we will validate some assumptions together, to get a sense of where your product is, and where it could go.
I’ll provide focused, practical feedback, and propose some directions.
In return you help me map the state of usability in open source, and we all help community by doing something for commons.
Reach out if:  Your project reached a plateau, and needs traction You&amp;rsquo;re lost on which features to focus on, and need a roadmap You are a dev with no personalproject and considering starting one, and needs help deciding on what&amp;rsquo;s needed/wanted  This offer is only valid for non profit, open source projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/care-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/care-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>The Politics of Interdependence 1. Caring Politics  we must elaborate a feminist, queer, anti-racist and eco-socialist perspective
  the very wealthy retain their full sense of agency, having the capacity to dominate or sack and replace those who care for them.
  punitive humiliation
  Dependence on care has been pathologised, rather than recognised as part of our human condition
  autonomy and independence have historically been lionised in the Global North and gendered ‘male’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy and Simulation</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/philosophy-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/philosophy-simulation/</guid>
      <description>The Emergence of Synthetic Reason Introduction Emergence in History  the absence of novelty in physical interactions meant that explaining their effects could be reduced to deduction from general principles or laws
  But the synthesis of water does produce something new, not new in the absolute sense of something that has never existed before but only in the relative sense that something emerges that was not in the interacting entities acting as causes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying with the Trouble</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/staying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/staying/</guid>
      <description>Making Kin in the Chthulucene  “to stir up,” “to make cloudy,” “to disturb.”
  The task is to make kin in lines of inventive connection as a practice of learning to live and die well with each other in a thick present
  Staying with the trouble does not require such a relationship to times called the future
  Nothing in kainos must mean conventional pasts, presents, or futures</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimeras</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/chimeras/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/chimeras/</guid>
      <description>Inventory of Synthetic Cognition  Modernist terms of linearity, sequentiality, separability, temporality, and spatiality
  Modernity’s efforts to legitimate the violent rationalities and acts of colonialism
  Refusal to install the application would automatically lower the social trust rating of the individual
  equates being seen with being protected
  ideological weaponization against the Other
  biometrical nudity
  the goal of “Safety” can be seen as labor exploitation for economic benefits</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Dreams</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/machine-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/machine-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Economics Becomes a Cyborg Science  cyborg science tended to parse its dynamics in terms of basins of attraction; due to its ontological commitment to dissipation, it imagined situations where a plurality of attractors existed, with the codicil that stochastic consid- erations could tip a system from one to another instantaneously
  To those seeking a new theory of social organization, the neoclassicals retorted that all effective organizations were merely disguised versions of their notion of an ur-market</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marx in the Anthropocene</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/marx-anthropocene/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/marx-anthropocene/</guid>
      <description>Towards the Idea of Degrowth Communism  fundamental materialist claim about the continuity of nature and humanity
  When the ideal of scientific knowledge is applied to nature it simply furthers the progress of science. But when it is applied to society it turns out to be ideological weapon of the bourgeoisie
  immediacy. Nature appears as given and can be objectively known as ‘pure facts
  total quantification of the world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dawn of Everything</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/dawn/</guid>
      <description>A New History of Humanity 2 Wicked Liberty: The indigenous critique and the myth of progress  They brand us for slaves, and call us miserable souls, whose life is not worth having, alleging that we degrade ourselves in subjecting ourselves to one man [the king] who possesses all the power, and is bound by no law but his own will.
  Power over possessions could be directly translated into power over other human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diamond Age</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/diamond-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/diamond-age/</guid>
      <description>Or, A Young Lady&amp;rsquo;s Illustrater Primer </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways of Being</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/being/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/being/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Human Intelligence 3: The Thicket of Life  there was no clean species break, but rather a gradual and drawn-out speciation process
  a ‘ghost population’ of ancient humans living half a million years ago
  a Neanderthal instrument
  Göbekli Tepe
  other-than-human beings.
  intermingling and interbreeding
  the glacial winters of the Pleistocene
  not a rigid map, but a pattern of interference</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>focus test</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/focus-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/focus-test/</guid>
      <description>Disregard font and icons. This is just a test to be deleted soon
primary button secondary button   checkbox checkbox, selected radio radio, selected </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gallery scroll</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/gallery-scroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/gallery-scroll/</guid>
      <description>const html = document.documentElement; const canvas = document.getElementById(&#34;gallery-scroll&#34;); const context = canvas.getContext(&#34;2d&#34;); const frameCount = 148; const currentFrame = index = ( `https://www.apple.com/105/media/us/airpods-pro/2019/1299e2f5_9206_4470_b28e_08307a42f19b/anim/sequence/large/01-hero-lightpass/${index.toString().padStart(4, &#39;0&#39;)}.jpg` ) const preloadImages = () = { for (let i = 1; i { img.src = currentFrame(index); context.drawImage(img, 0, 0); } window.addEventListener(&#39;scroll&#39;, () = { const scrollTop = html.scrollTop; const maxScrollTop = html.scrollHeight - window.innerHeight; const scrollFraction = scrollTop / maxScrollTop; const frameIndex = Math.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gallery scroll</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/test/</guid>
      <description>image 1
image 2
image 3
image 4
image 5
image 6
image 7
image 8
image 9
image 10
image 11
image 12
image 13
image 14
image 15
image 16
image 17
image 18
image 19
image 20
image 21
image 22
image 23
image 24
image 25
image 26
image 27
image 28
image 29
image 30
image 31
image 32
image 33
image 34
image 35</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVG SASS tiles</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/tile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/tile/</guid>
      <description>Vector tile library A vector pattern library mixin
How to use  Download and reference tile.scss on your scss/sass flow summon mixin with @include tile($type, $color, $size) with:  $type (required) as any type below $color (optional) as pattern color $size (optional) as size (play around)     .cross-a .cross-b .cross-c   .dots-a .dots-b .dots-c   .grid   .lines-a .lines-b .lines-c   .lines-down-a .lines-down-b .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>video scroll</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/video-scroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/play/video-scroll/</guid>
      <description> html { scroll-behavior: smooth; } #video { position: fixed; height: 100vh; } .scroll-dummy { height: 3000px; max-width: 998px; padding: 20px; z-index: 1; }       var FRAMES = 148; var FPS = 30; var video = document.getElementById(&#39;video&#39;); window.addEventListener(&#39;scroll&#39;, function (e) { var time = (window.scrollY / 1000) * FRAMES / FPS; video.currentTime = time; console.log(time); }); window.addEventListener(&#39;load&#39;, function(e) { video.pause(); video.currentTime = 0; }); </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zendegi</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/zendegi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/zendegi/</guid>
      <description>Whittling the collection down would feel like a kind of revisionism
  ‘Groundhog Cage’ she’d constructed that made thirty-day free-trial software think it was always on the first day of the trial
  I want to see if I can ride the coattails of the distribution
  So you’d be satisfied with passing as a low-affect psychopath, just so long as you don’t actually come across as brain-dead?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incomplete Nature</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/incomplete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 18:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/incomplete/</guid>
      <description>How Mind Emerged from Matter  But it is not simply a many-to-one relationship; it is the mapping of a continuum to discrete states. Morphodynamic work shares one very significant attribute with thermodynamic work: the law of diminishing returns. As this tendency to complexity becomes amplified to a far greater extend when we consider the superimposition of teleodynamic processes. how the evolutionary process is able to mine the morphodynamic domain for these sorts of reciprocities and complementarities In general terms, an orthograde teleodynamic process is an end-directed process, and more specifically, one that will tend to occur spontaneously new teleodynamic systems and relationships are generated from the interactions of prior teleodynamic systems with respect to their shared environmental contexts teleodynamic processes because they are end-directed toward specific target states orthograde because they are what organism dynamics produce naturally and spontaneously Organisms are of course highly complicated synergistic constellations of teleodynamic processes But like other forms of work, teleodynamic work can also be used to transform one form of teleodynamic process into another, and to generate emergent phenomena at a higher order And since all ultimately depend on thermodynamic work, this is the final arbiter of teleodynamic success evolution is a kind of teleodynamic engine This shift of work up-level, so to speak, significantly decreases the total amount of thermodynamic work to achieve this end The diversity of forms of teleodynamic work is as extensive as the fields of biology, psychology, human social behavior, and all the arts combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schilds Ladder</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/schilds-ladder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 18:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/schilds-ladder/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the quintessential singleton,&amp;rdquo; Cass replied. &amp;ldquo;I weigh up all my choices very carefully.&amp;rdquo;  April 30, 2016   Every viewpoint was a compromise, but she had to be as close as she could get.  May 1, 2016   What was the worst that one of these transient selves might do?  May 1, 2016   endless varieties of suffering, endless varieties of stupidity, endless varieties of banality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supersizing the mind</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/supersizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 18:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/supersizing/</guid>
      <description>Embodiment, Action, and Cognitive Extension  This is the thesis of the extended mind: when parts of the environment are coupled to the brain in the right way, they become parts of the mind. Parity Principle, which held that if aprocess in the world works in a way that we should count as a cognitive process if it were done in the head, then we should count it as a cognitive process all the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dispossessed</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/dispossessed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/dispossessed/</guid>
      <description>If the foreman had no experience in bossing a mob, they had no experience in being one.  December 24, 2016   A stone lay there. It was dark like the wall, but on it, or inside it, there was a number; and 5 he thought at first, then took it for 1 then understood what it was—the primal number, that was both unity and plurality. “That is the cornerstone  May 6, 2017   if I’m the prisoner, I can’t decide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angel Tech</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/angeltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/angeltech/</guid>
      <description>Undoing Yourself with Energized Meditation and Other Devices  the principle of Consciousness itself, which, like the god Hermes. . .travels between worlds without becoming residential to any of them.
 September 25, 2014
 Angel Tech was constructed much like a can-opener. What it describes is secondary to what it opens up as it reads
 September 25, 2014
 utter benevolence and surgical precision by which Life expresses itself through us</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Que o Cérebro Tem Para Contar</title>
      <link>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/cerebro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://***REMOVED***.github.io/book/cerebro/</guid>
      <description>Desvendando os Mistérios da Natureza Humana  Durante a maior parte do século XX, tudo o que tínhamos a oferecer em matéria de explicação do comportamento humano eram dois edifícios teóricos &amp;gt; o freudismo e o behaviorismo
 30 de outubro de 2016
 em sistemas biológicos há uma profunda unidade entre estrutura, função e origem. Não se pode fazer muito progresso na compreensão de qualquer desses aspectos a menos que se esteja também rigorosamente atento aos outros dois.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
